<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Imposter | Farish Kashefinejad]]></title>
  <link href="http://farishkash.com/blog/categories/imposter/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://farishkash.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-03-10T11:07:24-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://farishkash.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Farish Kashefinejad]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Road So far…(And a Little Story About Imposter Syndrome)]]></title>
    <link href="http://farishkash.com/blog/2015/03/10/the-road-so-far-dot-dot-dot-and-a-little-story-about-imposter-syndrome/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-10T09:40:57-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://farishkash.com/blog/2015/03/10/the-road-so-far-dot-dot-dot-and-a-little-story-about-imposter-syndrome</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So sometime around September 2014, I had made a decision to start a path towards a career change.  This has been building up for quite some time.  About 4 years ago I had released an iPhone app for IOS 4.  It was a tip calculator that split checks etc.</p>

<p>At that time I fell in love with the challenge of making a program.  Sadly after I had succeeded, I ran away from it.</p>

<p>This was always in the back of my mind.  I didn’t feel good enough or qualified enough.  I scared myself away.</p>

<p>So what happen in September of 2014?</p>

<p>I came across a thread on Reddit that talked about <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Impostor_syndrome">imposter syndrome</a>.  I was shocked. <!-- more --></p>

<p>My reaction was “This exists.  This is what I felt about myself, it isn’t just me.”</p>

<p>I bring up imposter syndrome for this reason.  I don’t know who may come across this blog.  If you are ever going to enter a difficult task in your life, you can not let self doubt and negativity get in the way of your goals.  We all have to learn how to break down our internal barriers in order to further ourselves for success.</p>

<p>So I began my journey into coding.  I started with online material like <a href="learnrubythehardway.org">learnrubythehardway.org</a>, <a href="codeacademy.com">codeacademy.com</a>, &amp; <a href="rubymonk.com">rubymonk.com</a>.</p>

<p>Then in Nov 2014 I saw the <a href="reskillusa.com">reskillusa.com</a> program announcement and signed up for their first run of the class.  They told me that the course was to get you in a better position to make the transition to developer.  They also informed me that the material was not comparable to other online courses but more of preparation tool for your next step.</p>

<p>I have to agree I feel more confident and my understanding of coding has grown leaps and bounds.  At the same time I feel that I need more guidance.</p>

<p>Now March has come and the class is wrapping up.  My next stop will be at <a href="thinkful.com">thinkful.com</a>.  In a future blog post I will discuss why I did choose them and a review of my experience with them.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
